All right, so there's just a couple of
additional terms I want to mention when it
comes to a schedule, a couple of
additional schedule management terms.
And these are not necessarily
terms that, you know,
you need to know about
in a huge amount of detail.
They just need to be aware of them.
And they're not really in a separate
category by themselves.
So that's why I just want to summarize
them all in one area here.
So the first term here, Gant chart,
right?
I'm sure many of you have come across Gant
charts before.
but many of you probably use Gant charts.
But a Gant chart is really just nothing
more than just a bar chart.
And it's just showing your schedule,
showing all the different schedule
activities, just showing the progress of
the schedule.
Right, you can use a
Gant chart initially to show
the proposed timeline
of different activities.
And then you can also use it to show the
actual progress against the timelines.
And a very simple example of a Gant chart
is shown here on this next slide here.
So you have your different activities.
down here on the left and side and then
you've got your timeline, you know,
just a very high level, month one,
month two, etc.
And these are just kind of like showing
you the progress, how we're progressing,
how these activities are progressing
against these different timelines.
Again, nothing that you need to know in a
huge amount of detail for the P&P exam.
I doubt they'll even ask you to interpret
a Gant chart.
You just need to know that it is there.
It is a tooling technique for the
schedule.
And generally, Gant charts
are going to be used more in
the predictive life cycle
rather than an agile life cycle.
There are other tools that we will be
talking about in Lesson 6, where we will,
there are other tools for Agar.
Now, another tool then is something called
milestone chart.
Very similar to a Gant chart.
Again, it's like a bar chart.
It's not like a bar chart.
It is a bar chart.
Very similar to a Gant chart, except this
time, they're showing milestones, right?
Whereas a Gant chart is showing individual
activities, the milestone chart is just
showing you milestones, you know, so
all the significant points on a project.
And that's what a milestone is.
A milestone is a key deliverable,
a significant point on a project.
Then you have this term here, law of
diminishing returns.
And I'm sure some of you have experienced
law of diminution returned before,
right?
But essentially, one unit of input does
not propose.
lead to one unit of output.
So doubling the number of
team members, for example, it's
not going to halve the time
in which to perform the work.
At some point, you know, there will be,
right, if you add in one more team member,
right, that will be a significant
increase.
Add on another team member, that would be
another significant increase, or rather
decrease, I should say a decrease in the
time to do the work.
But at some point, you're going to be
experiencing what's known
as diminishing returns.
It's just like, for example,
when you're studying,
when you're studying for this exam, right?
You're studying for the P&P exam.
When you're nice and fresh early in the
morning, right, your mind is fresh and you
study for two hours, you will get two
hours worth of work done, right?
Right at the end of the day, you've been
working all day, you come home,
you're a little, you know, maybe a little
stressed, maybe an untired, and now you
start studying, you might be looking at
the same page for two hours, right?
So, you know, you're not
really getting as much out of
studying as you would have
done, say, early in the morning.
Just to a very simple example.
Of course, everybody is different.
Every situation is different.
But that's what the law of diminishing
returns, refers to.
Then you've got Parkinson's Law,
this other term here, Parkinson's Law.
And Parkinson's Law, also
known as student syndrome,
right, or otherwise
known as procrastination.
and basically what that refers to is work
expands to fill the time available.
And it says here, right?
Work expands to fill the time available.
So in other words, you give somebody, say,
three weeks to perform a 10-hour task.
Well, guess what?
They will take three weeks to do it,
right?
As a general rule, you can expect that
they will take three weeks to do it.
They're not just going to sit down and
give it to you after 10 hours.
No, you have given them 10, you have given
them three weeks to perform this time.
task.
They know it's only going to take them 10
hours to do.
They'll do a couple of hours here,
a couple of hours there.
More than likely, what
they'll do is they'll leave
it all the way until the
last 10 hours, right?
And that's really what Parkinson's law
refers to.
Work will expand to fill the time
available.
So you give somebody a deadline.
And whatever that deadline
is, if it's a tight deadline,
team members will work
hard to meet that deadline.
If it's a long deadline, team members,
you know, we'll still meet that deadline,
but they'll deliver it during,
you know, they'll deliver it with by
whatever deadline you, or rather on the
deadline that you tell them.
Okay.
So these are just some additional terms.
Again, they're not in a separate category
anywhere, but they are part of schedule.
Just a couple of schedule management
terms.